<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/</link><description>Recent content on Home</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 23:17:32 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abudlightlime.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>牛肉麵, Wai Po's Beef Noodle Soup</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/post/20210331-beef-noodle-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 23:17:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/post/20210331-beef-noodle-soup/</guid><description>Figure 1. The chinese word biang comes from the sound that my heart makes when I see this dish
紅燒牛肉麵 Wai Po's Beef Noodle Soup (serves 6 people) ingredients: - soup - 6 quarts water - 2 lbs beef chuck (cut into 1 inch cubes) - 1 lb beef marrow bones (optional) - 3 tbsp vegetable oil - 1 garlic bulb in cloves - 2 inch piece ginger (sliced) - 1 stalk of scallions (quartered) - 2 tbsp doubanjiang (spicy bean paste) - 1/2 cup light soy sauce - 1/2 cup dark soy sauce - 1/2 cup shaoxing (or sweet cooking) wine - 1 yellow onion (peeled and halved) - 1 large tomato (quartered) - 1/2 an apple (decored) - 4 star anise - 2 chinese cinnamon sticks - 2 oz rock sugar - serving - flour noodles (cooked) - baby bok choy (blanched) - sesame oil (optional) - scallion (sliced) - tomato (sliced - 1 pint soup (heated) instructions: _soup_ 1.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes Web Deployments, a love story</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/post/20210330-k8s-web-deployments/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 21:37:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/post/20210330-k8s-web-deployments/</guid><description>The wrong tool for the job? Kubernetes is quickly becoming the default mechanism for engineers to manage remote deployments. Its feature-richness and ease of use make it an attractive solution for pushing work into the cloud. However, there still exist some quirks of its usage that any web developer should know before using it. This story tells of one of them.
Situation Suppose there was a web development team, who had decided to deploy their web application on kubernetes.</description></item><item><title>Hello Williamsburg</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/post/20210330-hello-williamsburg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 19:47:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/post/20210330-hello-williamsburg/</guid><description>Starting a blog After a little thinking - I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start a little blog. Hopefully I can add some meaningful content</description></item><item><title/><link>https://abudlightlime.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/about/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>