<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Belief on Home</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/tags/belief/</link><description>Recent content in Belief on Home</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 10:21:08 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abudlightlime.com/tags/belief/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Confidence</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20250701-confidence/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 10:21:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20250701-confidence/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s astounding how many people use the median of anything to figure out a budget. How much money to have in their bank account, how much time to dedicate to a project, when they should leave the home to be at work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Google maps uses the median of a distribution to estimate how long it takes to get somewhere. If you too, use that median, you&amp;rsquo;ll be late 50% of the time. You&amp;rsquo;ll overdraft your bank account in 50% of your paychecks. You&amp;rsquo;ll miss your deadline 50% of the time. And we ask ourselves, why, why does this keep happening? People are cripplingly stupid creatures.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Humanity</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20250701-humanity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 09:52:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20250701-humanity/</guid><description>&lt;p>Each one of us is born out of the earth, raised and nourished by it like a plant. Like a poppy, the child sprouts out of the ground and grows, its five tendrils on its few branches reaching out and grasping for things every single moment until it expires. We wrap around each other without consent, like the young ivy strangles the aging oak. In a fit of rage or fear, this plant lashes out and then is stupified when its actions are reciprocated.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>