<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Management on Home</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/tags/management/</link><description>Recent content in Management on Home</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 12:41:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abudlightlime.com/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>musings on the take home technical interview</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20230823-the-take-home-assignment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 12:41:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20230823-the-take-home-assignment/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="what-motivates-the-technical-take-home-test">What motivates the technical take home test?&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The take home exercise is an interviewing practice that&amp;rsquo;s existed for a while. It&amp;rsquo;s been around for a while in the form of a case study, and I&amp;rsquo;ve seen it personally as an open ended development exercise. If completed well, it provides a great deal of insight into how the candidate works. Like any practice though, it isn&amp;rsquo;t without its drawbacks. Aside from the issues companies face like cheating[1], take home interviews can artificially limit the prospective talent pool, in addition to self-select for dishonest candidates.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncertain Project Estimation</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20220106-better-project-estimation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 21:37:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20220106-better-project-estimation/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="what-makes-project-estimation-so-difficult">What makes project estimation so difficult?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Proper project estimation can be as much of an art as it is a science. Artistically, it requires that gut reaction when a seemingly simple project carries with it complexity undertones unseen. Scientifically however, it should be interpreted more like statistics than basic arithmetic. I say this because statistics is bound tightly to the principle of uncertainty and uncertainty is a highly valuable concept when understanding and communicating project commitments.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>