<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Home</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Home</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 17:07:42 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abudlightlime.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A curious claim about Advertising's effect on Google</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20221204-googles-claim-on-advertising/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 17:07:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20221204-googles-claim-on-advertising/</guid><description>Note: This article is presented in short form and long form in that order. Feel free to read whichever version you prefer.
Google, is it worse now? [short form] In a recently published Freakanomics episode about the perceived quality degradation of Google Search, Marissa Mayer makes a claim that ads made Google a more enjoyable product to Google users. This claim came as the conclusion of a long running experiment in which some users weren’t shown ads, and those shown ads used Google 3% more.</description></item><item><title>If not careful, A/B testing will kill innovation</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20220716-abtesting-and-innovation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jul 2022 15:34:22 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20220716-abtesting-and-innovation/</guid><description>Note: I substitued the phrase A/B Testing for experimentation in this document
I recently read an article on hacker news highlighting some of the anti-patterns of experimentation and it got me thinking about an idea that I’ve had bouncing around in my head for some time. The article begins to unwind some of the common risks with experimentation, which generally include ignoring the long term effects of experiments and only measuring part of what matters.</description></item><item><title>Wanna get better? Spend less time rubbernecking.</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20220703-rubberneck-debugging/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 16:26:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20220703-rubberneck-debugging/</guid><description>What is rubberneck debugging? Rubberneck debugging is something I see a lot of high achieving engineers fall trap to. Put simply, it’s the eagerness one might feel to respond to urgent inquiries in a forum like slack. I find that it tends to stifle the engineers growth, as well as diminishes the opportunities that newer and more junior engineers have to engage in public discussion.
What does it look like? I think we&amp;rsquo;ve all been in this situation before.</description></item><item><title>The Bacon Egg and Cheese, New York's Real Treasure</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20220302-bacon-egg-and-cheese/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 21:04:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20220302-bacon-egg-and-cheese/</guid><description>Figure 1. You may have heard of the full english or full irish, well this one I call the full long island.
Out on the island If you&amp;rsquo;re from around here, you know that we&amp;rsquo;re not in Long Island, we&amp;rsquo;re on Long Island. That train you take home isn&amp;rsquo;t the &amp;ldquo;lurr&amp;rdquo; like some city folk call it, it&amp;rsquo;s the &amp;ldquo;ell-eye-arr-arr&amp;rdquo; and you know for sure that any deli you walk into is going to make a fucking good bacon egg and cheese sandwich.</description></item><item><title>Uncertain Project Estimation</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20220106-better-project-estimation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 21:37:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20220106-better-project-estimation/</guid><description>What makes project estimation so difficult? Proper project estimation can be as much of an art as it is a science. Artistically, it requires that gut reaction when a seemingly simple project carries with it complexity undertones unseen. Scientifically however, it should be interpreted more like statistics than basic arithmetic. I say this because statistics is bound tightly to the principle of uncertainty and uncertainty is a highly valuable concept when understanding and communicating project commitments.</description></item><item><title>Your first rotation oncall as a Software Engineer</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20211224-your-first-oncall-rotation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 21:37:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20211224-your-first-oncall-rotation/</guid><description>I think most engineers remember this first time oncall. If you&amp;rsquo;re writing software at any larger organization, oncall is a way for the company to delegate critical issues and shield teams from unexpected interruptions. I found this helpful guide](https://brianjenney.medium.com/how-to-survive-your-first-on-call-rotation-as-a-software-engineer-5bc0d334566e) detailing a lot of the ideas I share, and hope that this document can serve as an affirmation and compliment to that one.
What to do I want to highlight the most important idea about oncall that I feel not everyone knows.</description></item><item><title>炸醬麵 Zha Jiang Mian</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20211223-zha-jiang-mian/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Dec 2021 23:17:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20211223-zha-jiang-mian/</guid><description>Figure 1. A classic and tasy Chinese noodle dish
炸醬麵 Ma&amp;#39;s Zha Jiang Mian (Serves 6) ingredients: - sauce - 2 tbsp vegetable oil - 1 scallion (finely diced) - 3 garlic cloves (finely minced) - 1/2 in cube ginger (finely minced) - 1lb ground pork (or turkey) - 2 heaping tbsp dou ban jiang (bean paste) - 2 heaping tbsp tian mian jiang (sweet bean paste) - 1/2 tomato (diced) - 1 cup greenbeans (diced) - 2 cup dry tofu (diced) - 2 cups water - serving - flour noodles (cooked) - sauce - scallions (diced) - cucumber (cut into little sticks) - scrambled egg (cut into ribbons) instructions: _sauce_ 1.</description></item><item><title>Diagnosing MySQL deadlocks</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20211126-diagnosing-mysql-deadlocks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 19:02:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20211126-diagnosing-mysql-deadlocks/</guid><description>An unpleasant exception Deadlock found when trying to get lock; try restarting transaction If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this document, you&amp;rsquo;re either here out of curiosity or necessity. I&amp;rsquo;ll be brief for those in the latter camp. When you encounter the above error in production, you only need the stack trace to figure out which query got blocked. What I have found is difficult to ascertain is which query is doing the actual blocking.</description></item><item><title>Kubernetes Web Deployments, a love story</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20211028-k8s-web-deployments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 21:37:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20211028-k8s-web-deployments/</guid><description>The wrong tool for the job? Kubernetes is quickly becoming the default mechanism for engineers to manage remote deployments. Its feature-richness and ease of use make it an attractive solution for pushing work into the cloud. However, there still exist some quirks of its usage that any web developer should know before using it. This story tells of one of them.
What happens on Deployment For anyone who knows kubernetes, you&amp;rsquo;ll know that service deployments are rolled out in sets of pods.</description></item><item><title>牛肉麵, Wai Po's Beef Noodle Soup</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20211015-beef-noodle-soup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 23:17:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20211015-beef-noodle-soup/</guid><description>Figure 1. The chinese word biang comes from the sound that my heart makes when I see this dish
紅燒牛肉麵 Wai Po&amp;#39;s Beef Noodle Soup (serves 6 people) ingredients: - soup - 6 quarts water - 2 lbs beef chuck (cut into 1 inch cubes) - 1 lb beef marrow bones (optional) - 3 tbsp vegetable oil - 1 garlic bulb in cloves - 2 inch piece ginger (sliced) - 1 stalk of scallions (quartered) - 2 tbsp doubanjiang (spicy bean paste) - 1/2 cup light soy sauce - 1/2 cup dark soy sauce - 1/2 cup shaoxing (or sweet cooking) wine - 1 yellow onion (peeled and halved) - 1 large tomato (quartered) - 1/2 an apple (decored) - 4 star anise - 2 chinese cinnamon sticks - 2 oz rock sugar - serving - flour noodles (cooked) - baby bok choy (blanched) - sesame oil (optional) - scallion (sliced) - tomato (sliced - 1 pint soup (heated) instructions: _soup_ 1.</description></item><item><title>Hello Williamsburg</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20210330-hello-williamsburg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 19:47:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20210330-hello-williamsburg/</guid><description>Starting a blog After a little thinking - I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start a little blog. Hopefully I can add some meaningful content</description></item></channel></rss>