<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Soup on Home</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/tags/soup/</link><description>Recent content in Soup on Home</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 23:17:32 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abudlightlime.com/tags/soup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>牛肉麵, Wai Po's Beef Noodle Soup</title><link>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20211015-beef-noodle-soup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 23:17:32 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://abudlightlime.com/posts/20211015-beef-noodle-soup/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://abudlightlime.com/img/beef-noodle-soup-biang.jpg" alt="Taiwan&amp;rsquo;s treat in brooklyn">
&lt;strong>Figure 1. The chinese word biang comes from the sound that my heart makes when I see this dish&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre tabindex="0">&lt;code>紅燒牛肉麵
Wai Po&amp;#39;s Beef Noodle Soup
(serves 6 people)

ingredients:
 - soup
 - 6 quarts water
 - 2 lbs beef chuck (cut into 1 inch cubes)
 - 1 lb beef marrow bones (optional)
 - 3 tbsp vegetable oil
 - 1 garlic bulb in cloves
 - 2 inch piece ginger (sliced)
 - 1 stalk of scallions (quartered)
 - 2 tbsp doubanjiang (spicy bean paste)
 - 1/2 cup light soy sauce
 - 1/2 cup dark soy sauce
 - 1/2 cup shaoxing (or sweet cooking) wine
 - 1 yellow onion (peeled and halved)
 - 1 large tomato (quartered)
 - 1/2 an apple (decored)
 - 4 star anise
 - 2 chinese cinnamon sticks
 - 2 oz rock sugar
 - serving
 - flour noodles (cooked)
 - baby bok choy (blanched)
 - sesame oil (optional)
 - scallion (sliced)
 - tomato (sliced
 - 1 pint soup (heated)

instructions:
_soup_
1. Bring 8 quarts of water to a boil. Blanche and rinse the beef bones / chuck in batches. Set them aside for now.
2. In a large pot on high heat, bring the vegetable oil to near the smoking point. Flash fry the ginger, garlic and scallions for roughly 1 minute.
3. Add the doubanjiang to the pot and continue stirring the mixture for 1-2 mins, trying not to burn the sauce.
 - *Note*: This step aresolizes the spice from the doubanjiang. Make sure to turn on your vent for this step.
4. Add the dark and light soy to the pot. Add the beef to the pot as well and mix thoroughly to coat the meat in the mixture. Let cook for another 3-4 minutes.
5. Add the 6 quarts of water and the cooking wine to the pot. Bring it up to a boil and then lower the heat to medium.
6. Let the soup cook for another 1-4 hours depending on how tender you want the beef to be. Make sure to add water periodically as the broth should be at a rolling boil.
7. In the last 30 minutes of the boil, add the apple and rock sugar to the soup.
8. Strain the soup into a serving or storage container. Set the beef aside and discard the rest of the stew materials.

_serving_
1. Ensure that the broth is either just hot from cooking, or being heated before mixing the ingredients.
2. In a pot of boiling water, cook the noodles to just before done and set aside.
3. Using that same pot of boiling water, blanche the bok choy (or other leafy green) and set aside.
4. In a large bowl, add the beef and noodles side by side. Drizzle a splash of sesame oil on top and add the broth, bok choy, tomato and scallions.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://abudlightlime.com/img/beef-noodle-soup.jpg" alt="With spaghetti">
&lt;strong>Figure 2. Mmmmmmmmmm&lt;/strong>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>